<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
    xmlns:ns="http://oursite/ns">
    <teiHeader>
        <!-- early on, we can probably not worry about adding in lots of the teiHeader info -->
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Title</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <p>Publication Information</p>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>Information about the source(s)</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <!-- I think the right place to gather metadata will be in the encodingDesc. Would appreciate it if others with TEI skill commented about that. -->


        <ns:layoutDesc> </ns:layoutDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <!-- We'll figure out what to put into the revision description when other people figure out how they want to handle it. Since this is the cool political part, we'll put it in our namespace -->
        </revisionDesc>
        <encodingDesc>

            <refsDecl>
                <ab type="metadata" subtype="contributors">
                    <!-- the anonymous block might be the best way hold metadata about people (and more?) without making TEI mad -->
                    <listPerson>
                        <person xml:id="boonebgorges" role="admin">
                            <persName>
                                <forename>Boone</forename>
                                <surname>Borges</surname>
                                <name>Boone B Gorges</name>
                                <addName type="username">boonebgorges</addName>
                                <addName type="uri">http://example.com/users/boonebgorges</addName>
                            </persName>
                            <sex>yes please</sex>

                        </person>
                        <person xml:id="patrickmj" role="contributor">
                            <persName>
                                <forename>Patrick</forename>
                            </persName>
                        </person>
                    </listPerson>
                </ab>

            </refsDecl>
            <appInfo>
                <application ident="namehere" version="1.0">
                    <label>Oneweek Thingy</label>
                </application>
            </appInfo>


        </encodingDesc>

    </teiHeader>
    <text>

        <body>
            <!-- TEI @type is designed to be free-form, the content coming from WP will go into @type="post". Everything else we can keep loose and extendable -->
            <div type="part">
                <head>
                    <title>Division title</title>
                    <bibl>
                        <author ref="boone"></author>
                    </bibl>
                </head>
                <!-- @type="post" says this is coming from the post. Down the road, we might have ways to TEI-ize the post itself, in which case @subtype="tei" -->
                <div type="post" subtype="html">

                    <html:body>

                        <html:p>My name is Boone Gorges and Teleogistic is my personal
                            blog.</html:p>

                        <html:p>I am a PhD student in <html:a
                                href="http://web.gc.cuny.edu/Philosophy/">philosophy</html:a> at the
                                <html:a href="http://www.gc.cuny.edu">CUNY Graduate
                            Center</html:a>.</html:p>

                        <html:p>I am a WordPress developer specializing in BuddyPress. I am
                            currently the lead developer for the <html:a
                                href="http://commons.gc.cuny.edu">CUNY Academic
                            Commons</html:a></html:p>

                        <html:p>In a previous incarnation, I was an instructional designer at
                                <html:a href="http://www.qc.cuny.edu">CUNY Queens
                            College</html:a>.</html:p>

                        <html:p>On this blog I talk about philosophy, technology, education,
                            etc.</html:p>

                        <html:p>You can email me if you want to shoot the breeze. Combine my Twitter
                            handle (located in the left sidebar of this page) with
                            @gmail.com.</html:p>

                    </html:body>
                </div>


                <div type="post" subtype="html">
                    <body xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                        <p>I had an interesting conversation last night regarding using Facebook to
                            communicate with students. There are lots of interesting aspects of this
                            question, many of them of a practical type (how can I keep my students
                            from seeing pictures of me getting drunk?) with practical answers (learn
                            to use privacy settings). My sense is that if you could survey
                            professors who are uneasy with the idea of Facebooking with their
                            students, this would be the most prevalent cause for concern.</p>

                        <p>Much more interesting to me, though, is a different kind of worry, this
                            one tied to the educational goals of the academy. The communication that
                            happens in Facebook, the argument goes, is brief (think status updates),
                            unnuanced, unsensitive to audience, overly informal. The communicative
                            style that we want to teach our students, on the other hand, is nuanced
                            and professional, both because this kind of communication is
                            intrinsically better (whatever that might mean) and because it's the
                            kind of communication that they will have to be fluent in in order to
                            flourish in the real world.</p>

                        <p>The motivation here seems right: we want to teach our students to be
                            communicators who are sensitive to voice and audience and thus more
                            likely to be successful. That said, there's nothing inherent to Facebook
                            that precludes this kind of conduct. I might even argue that the fact
                            that students typically use the medium in non-academic ways makes it
                            even <em>more</em> valuable as a teaching tool. In the "real world", the
                            division between professional and non-professional communication does
                            not fall neatly along the lines that delineate media; telephone calls,
                            emails, and face-to-face interactions are all used both for talking shop
                            and for informal purposes. What students need to learn is not that
                            certain media are appropriate for certain kinds of exchanges, but rather
                            how to adapt to different kinds of exchanges regardless of the medium.
                            Using Facebook to communicate with students is a potentially fertile
                            ground for these lessons.</p>

                        <p>The distinction between "professional" and "non-professional" exchanges
                            is bunk anyway. Even the idea that there is a continuum from totally
                            formal communication to totally informal communication oversimplifies
                            the matter. Relationships differ along all sorts of various dimensions,
                            and to paint a caricature of this to students is both dishonest and
                            self-defeating.</p>

                        <p>This isn't to say that spaces like Facebook don't provide any new
                            rhetorical challenges. It's hard to find a non-web-2.0 analog for status
                            updates: brief, frequent messages that are sent to an entire network of
                            individuals with whom you have different kinds of relationships. But
                            this too is a teaching opportunity. Students should understand the
                            quasi-public nature of these messages, and the technological means of
                            making them less public if they wish.</p>

                        <p>It's an open question whether it's a good idea for any given professor to
                            use this medium to communicate with students. But to rule it out across
                            the board doesn't seem right either, at least not for the reasons I talk
                            about here.</p>

                    </body>
                </div>

                <div type="post" subtype="html">
                    <body xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                        <p>Thanks for not posting about Kripke, Kalynne! Not that I don't
                                <em>love</em> to think about him. (Speaking of Kripke, I just read a
                            brief article in this book <a
                                href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0195323262/experimentalp-20"
                                rel="nofollow"><em>Experimental Philosophy</em></a> about how the
                            intuition of East Asians to Kripke's Gödel example is not nearly as
                            overwhelmingly anti-descriptivist as the corresponding intuition of
                            Westerners. Pretty interesting.)</p>

                        <p>I like your blog entry but I'm afraid that it wouldn't apply to my own
                            life very much! Maybe I should work on my own What I Do: An Explanation
                            for the Folk.</p>

                        <p>As for Blatz: It's all my grandfather buys. I can't get it in Brooklyn so
                            I enjoy it as much as I can when I'm here in northern WI. Rather,
                            "enjoy".</p>

                    </body>
                </div>
            </div>


            <div type="part">


                <div type="post" subtype="html">
                    <body xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">

                        <p>I just read <a
                                href="http://www.internetnews.com/commentary/print.php/3793561">this
                                piece by Mike Elgan</a>. Elgan's argument is that hard work is dead
                            in an age where we have Twitter, Facebook, email, etc. to constantly and
                            effortlessly distract us.</p>

                        <p>There seems to be a mistake in this reasoning. If all that's changed from
                            now and the golden age of hard work (whenever that might have been) is
                            that we have more media for distraction at hand, what follows
                            immediately is that people were <em>less distracted</em> in the good old
                            days. But to say that someone is less distracted doesn't suggest
                            anything about their "work ethic" without some meaty assumptions.</p>

                        <p>The lack of distractions (or, to put it in more neutral terms, the lack
                            of alternative avenues for your attention!): this sounds like the very
                            definition of boredom. But boredom - a state you find yourself in -
                            isn't directly related to how hard you work - a choice you make. It's
                            true that boredom might drive you to devote your energies to something
                            in the way that exemplifies a good work ethic, but on the other hand it
                            might not, and you might end up staring at the wall as I so often do. On
                            the flip side, someone who is never bored (i.e. is constantly
                            distracted) might well be working very hard all the time. Anyone who
                            tries to keep up with their feed reader knows how hard you have to work
                            to maintain a respectably high level of distraction.</p>

                        <p>More importantly, though, the assumption that there is something holy
                            about the work ethic of our grandparents is off. Work ethics are not
                            inherently valuable; they only derive value from their products. Thus,
                            for example, a writer's work ethic is valuable because of the things
                            that she writes, or even the kind of person she becomes as a result of
                            this work ethic. But things like good writing and being a good person
                            are, as philosophers are wont to say, multiply realizable, and while
                            it's true that the supposed tunnel vision of our forebears sometimes
                            resulted in the kind of work that is independently valuable, it doesn't
                            mean that equally good or better work can't come out of more
                            distributed, "distracted" processes.</p>

                        <p>Isn't it at least conceivable that, for instance, an obsessed Twitter
                            user might write a poem that is not only as good as a more "focused"
                            poet, but one that would be impossible without something like
                            Twitter?</p>

                        <p>This is not to say that I don't think total focus is not valuable. I do
                            think, however, that distraction can have value too, or at least that
                            the question is an empirical one.</p>

                    </body>
                </div>

                <div type="post" subtype="html">
                    <body xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"> I've been reading the comments on <a
                            href="http://leiterreports.typepad.com/blog/2009/01/do-young-philos.html"
                            >this post</a> at Brian Leiter's blog (via <a
                            href="http://sympoze.com/node/534">Sympoze</a>). It's been exhausting on
                        several levels. If you read a few of the comments for yourself, I think
                        you'll understand why. <a
                            href="http://flickr.com/photos/meghannfinn/2829017064/"><img
                                class="size-medium wp-image-36"
                                title="Video and tanning - together at last"
                                src="http://teleogistic.net/wp-content/uploads/2009/01/2829017064_3dc07a4c76-300x225.jpg"
                                alt="Together at last - via &lt;a href=" width=" mce_href="
                                height="225" style="float:right;"></img></a>Of particular interest
                        to me is the explicit invocation (<a
                            href="http://leiterreports.typepad.com/blog/2009/01/do-young-philos.html#comment-144511172"
                            >here</a> and <a
                            href="http://leiterreports.typepad.com/blog/2009/01/do-young-philos.html#comment-144541410"
                            >here</a>, among other places) of the distinction between research and
                        teaching, and between departments where one or the other of these practices
                        is emphasized. What's the connection between the two? Practically speaking,
                        someone who wants to do philosophical research and is not independently
                        wealthy must, in the vast majority of cases, teach as well. Likewise,
                        someone who wants to teach philosophy to undergraduates must, in the vast
                        majority of cases, go through a very research-centric graduate education
                        and, if he wants eventual job security, engage in research for the purpose
                        of publication. Are these connections de jure or merely de facto? Are there
                        principled reasons why there should be such intricate links between
                        teaching- and research-based careers, or are the connections the result of
                        historical and economic accident? I thought I'd try to articulate some of
                        the ties between teaching philosophy and doing philosophical research. Feel
                        free to jump in if you can think of any more. <strong>Why researchers must
                            teach</strong>
                        <ul>
                            <li>The most obvious explanation is that philosophy (alas!) doesn't pay:
                                original philosophical research typically doesn't make the NYT
                                best-seller list, and the market for philosophers to the royal court
                                is depressingly lackluster. Universities need people to teach
                                philosophy, and practicing philosophers are a captive work pool. If
                                this were the only explanation for why philosophers teach then we
                                would certainly say that the combined vocation is an economic
                                accident.</li>
                            <li>I've had a few classes in graduate school that were built around a
                                draft of a book being written by the professor. The class works like
                                a testing ground for the draft. The philosopher thus gets to use his
                                teaching in order to advance and improve his work. So this is a
                                reason why teaching might be useful to a practicing
                                philosopher.</li>
                            <li>More generally speaking, it might be argued that teaching -
                                including the process of explaining something you know well to a
                                bunch of people who don't know it all that well - enhances one's own
                                understanding of, and ability to articulate, what one knows or
                                believes. This explanatory skill is important for the writer of
                                philosophy.</li>
                            <li>Philosophical researchers presumably care about the health of the
                                discipline of philosophy, and in particular the <em>future</em>
                                health of the discipline. The future of philosophy is dependent on
                                future philosophers, and future philosophers come from the general
                                student pool. Thus philosophers have a vested interest in making
                                sure that at least these students get a decent philosophical
                                training. (The big premise here is that philosophers care about the
                                discipline as a whole. I wonder how true this actually is.)</li>
                        </ul> I might note in passing that these last three reasons explain why
                        philosophers <em>ought to want</em> to teach, while the first reason
                        explains why philosophers <em>are required</em> to teach. If the benefits
                        gleaned from the "ought to want" category could be guaranteed in a different
                        way, then it's hard to see how there is any necessary connection between
                        research and teaching in this direction. <strong>Why teachers must
                            research</strong>
                        <ul>
                            <li>In order to teach effectively, you must have a certain mastery of
                                your subject (or, at least, there has to be a certain differential
                                between your mastery and your students'). Mastery in philosophy
                                comes down to the ability to read texts, understand problems,
                                construct arguments, and so on. These skills are best developed
                                through the kinds of research that philosophers do. So research is
                                good job training.</li>
                            <li>One of the reasons why philosophy is taught widely is to locate and
                                train the next generation of philosophical researchers. Instructors
                                with no knowledge of how philosophical research is done won't be
                                able to spot potential philosophers and hone them for the
                                field.</li>
                            <li>More broadly, doing philosophy in a classroom is not really that
                                different from doing philosophy in the armchair. You're still
                                reading those texts and still constructing those arguments. The
                                practice of teaching philosophy might be a somewhat watered-down
                                version of "real" research, but it's not fundamentally different. If
                                you want to be able to <em>teach</em> philosophy, you need to be
                                able to <em>do</em> philosophy, since teaching and doing philosophy
                                are essentially the same thing and, you know, the indiscernability
                                of identicals. (The immediate problem I see with this is that
                                teaching old arguments is crucially different from developing new
                                arguments, at least from the point of view of the teacher's
                                epistemic states. Contributing something new to the debate, as
                                researchers do, is generally something altogether over and above the
                                argumentation that is done in classrooms.)</li>
                        </ul> It's hard to draw a definitive conclusion from these considerations.
                        All things being equal, the more de jure connections you can point to
                        between philosophical research and philosophical teaching, the more
                        justified the de facto connection between the two vocations becomes. On the
                        other hand, it remains an open question whether there might be other models
                        for philosophers: a way for individuals to do research outside of the
                        university, a way for individuals to teach philosophy without the rigors of
                        a research-based education. Since people come to philosophy for different
                        reasons, wouldn't it make sense to have different career paths? </body>
                </div>


            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
